<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bootcamp on Caleb Jay&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.calebjay.com/tags/bootcamp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bootcamp on Caleb Jay&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 01:16:47 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.calebjay.com/tags/bootcamp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Programmers Should Read Hacker News</title>
      <link>http://blog.calebjay.com/posts/new-programmers-should-read-hacker-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 01:16:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.calebjay.com/posts/new-programmers-should-read-hacker-news/</guid>
      <description>I went through a coding bootcamp, and coming out, one of my greatest weaknesses was a lack of breadth of general technical knowledge. I was an active redditor and nerd in general so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t totally lost, but I noticed during meetups there were a lot of conversations I simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t participate in in a meaningful way because of my noobiness. When I went to a Hackathon, I watched people talk about technologies and solutions I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even aware existed - the classic &amp;ldquo;what I don&amp;rsquo;t know I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use LinkedIn as a Coding Bootcamp Grad</title>
      <link>http://blog.calebjay.com/posts/how-to-use-linkedin-as-a-coding-bootcamp-grad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 00:16:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.calebjay.com/posts/how-to-use-linkedin-as-a-coding-bootcamp-grad/</guid>
      <description>LinkedIn is the ubiquitous job-search tool recommended by everyone, ever, for a reason - it&amp;rsquo;s useful. I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you how I used it, and I got a job out of Hack Reactor pretty quick, so trust me on this stuff. Out of everything that goes into a job search as a coding bootcamp grad, using LinkedIn is what I&amp;rsquo;m most confident in.
Imagine an A-10 Warthog:
https://www.youtube.com/embed/lCCty8DpUwk
It&amp;rsquo;s a gun that the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How this Coding Bootcamp Grad Found a Job</title>
      <link>http://blog.calebjay.com/posts/how-this-coding-bootcamp-grad-found-a-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 02:16:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.calebjay.com/posts/how-this-coding-bootcamp-grad-found-a-job/</guid>
      <description>I went to a coding bootcamp, and then I got hired. I want others to be able to do the same thing, so I will illustrate in as much detail as I am comfortable the things I did that I think led to me getting a job in ~1 month after graduating from a coding bootcamp. This will be one part of a many part series going over how I transformed from a Liberal Arts degree holder making 40k/year as a recruiter into a Software Engineer making ~120k/year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Texas Bootcamp Grad&#39;s First Days at a Silicon Valley Startup</title>
      <link>http://blog.calebjay.com/posts/a-texas-bootcamp-grads-first-days-at-a-silicon-valley-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 16:16:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.calebjay.com/posts/a-texas-bootcamp-grads-first-days-at-a-silicon-valley-startup/</guid>
      <description>A month ago, I finished out at Hack Reactor / Makersquare. Two days ago, I started working at Electric Imp.
This city is different, these companies are different. In Houston, I was a recruiter in Oil and Gas - visualize an open work space with meetings about KPIs, people constantly on the phone. Headsets. A prominently displayed whiteboard with sales targets. British people in suits. Coming into work at 7:15, leaving at 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Place, New Job</title>
      <link>http://blog.calebjay.com/posts/new-place-new-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 01:16:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.calebjay.com/posts/new-place-new-job/</guid>
      <description>I start working at Electric Imp tomorrow. Their business model is essentially selling IoT hardware (think Nest, lights you can turn on and off with your smartphone, etc) and enabling connectivity between that hardware and their cloud service, which allows programming of that hardware. It was a hard decision. I was fortunate in that I had several other promising offers - the most first world problem I ever had, really. In the end my decision boiled down to do I want to be a small gear in a big machine, or a big gear in a small machine?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>